Guide to the John Howard Melish, William Howard Melish and Protestant Episcopal Church of the Holy Trinity collection ARC.050
Brooklyn Historical Society
- Series 8: Publications., 1913-1985; 0.45 Linear feet
  The series contains various publications. The first folder in the series contains a few pamphlets authored by John Howard Melish. The next few folders contain pamphlets and sermons authored by William Howard Melish. These include Melish's recollections in 1960 of civil rights activism in the South; notes from Melish relating to the materials in the series, including one referencing how part of Arthur Miller's work The Crucible was written in the Melish home; and Melish's recollections of W. E. B. Du Bois. Some miscellaneous publications follow, which include Father and Son, a pamphlet written by Arthur Miller in support of the Melishes. Next in the series is a folder of press releases from the years of the Melish Case. Next is a run of Parish News from 1946-1959, and The Churchman from 1948-1963. Finally, a few copies of The Witness are included.
  The series is arranged with Melish writings followed by other printed matter.
  - John Howard Melish Publications., 1913, 1941-1954 (Box 14, Folder 5)
  - William Howard Melish Sermons and Speeches., 1947-1963, 1980-1985 (Box 14, Folder 6)
  - Melish Case: Challenge to the Church., circa 1949 (Box 14, Folder 7)
  - The Story of a Congregation., circa 1950 (Box 14, Folder 8)
  - Miscellaneous Publications., 1949-1959 (Box 14, Folder 9)
  - Press Releases., 1947-1961 (Box 14, Folder 10)
  - The Parish News., 1946-1956 (Box 14, Folder 11)
  - The Parish News., 1957 (Box 15, Folder 1)
  - The Parish News., 1958-1959 (Box 15, Folder 2)
  - The Churchman., 1948-1957 (Box 15, Folder 3)
  - The Churchman., 1958-1963 (Box 15, Folder 4)
  - The Witness., 1950, 1955 (Box 15, Folder 5)
- Series 9: Court Records., 1949-1979; 0.75 Linear feet
  The series primarily includes the printed court records from the Supreme Court of Kings County concerning the Melish case. Two of the main types of documents included here are briefs and memorandums from the various court cases, and several copies of some of these can be found in different folders. Two copies of Records on Appeal from a 1949 case are in the series, as are lists of thousands of American clergymen who put their names forward to oppose or support a particular case. Some records from Touchet's research are in this series, including a letter to a judge who was involved in the case, some handwritten notes from an interview, and a chronology of newspaper stories from 1949-1956.
  - Court Records, Notes by Francis H. Touchet., 1949-1979 (Box 15, Folder 6)
  - Legal Papers of the Defense Committee., 1949-1956 (Box 15, Folder 7)
  - Court Records., 1949-1950 (Box 15, Folder 8)
  - Court Records., 1956-1959 (Box 16, Folder 1)
  - Record on Appeal., 1949 (Box 16, Folder 2)
  - Record on Appeal (Duplicate)., 1949 (Box 16, Folder 3)